<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata><NPS_Info><MetaPurp>NPS</MetaPurp><NPS_Unit><UnitCode>ROMO </UnitCode><UnitType>Park </UnitType></NPS_Unit><DatStore><Category>Digital Elevation Model by Quad </Category></DatStore><Std_Info><SObjName>MANDATORY: Name of NRDT or GIS Layer Standard</SObjName><SType>MANDATORY: Standard Type (GIS or NRDT)</SType><StatInfo><SStatus>MANDATORY: Standard Status</SStatus></StatInfo></Std_Info></NPS_Info><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Rocky Mountain National Park GIS Program</origin><pubdate>19950101</pubdate><title>Seamless 30-Meter Digital Elevation Model for Rocky Mountain National Park</title><serinfo><sername>none</sername><issue>none</issue></serinfo><pubinfo><pubplace>Estes Park, Colorado</pubplace><publish>Rocky Mountain National Park GIS Program</publish></pubinfo><onlink Sync="TRUE">\\10.147.158.195\ROMN\PROJECTS\ROMN\158_ROMN_CostSurfaceModelDevelopment\Data\original_data\romo_dem30.img</onlink><geoform Sync="TRUE">remote-sensing image</geoform><ftname Sync="TRUE">romo_dem30.img</ftname></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This data is a seamless Digital Elevation Model (DEM) that depicts the surface elevation in and around Rocky Mountain National Park. It is in ARC/INFO lattice format. The resolution for this data is 30 meters per cell. This data covers a 25 quad area centered on ROMO. The 25 7.5 minute USGS quads covered are: Clark Peak, Chambers Lake, Comanche Peak, Pingree Park, Crystal Mountain, Mount Richthofen, Fall River Pass, Trail Ridge, Estes Park, Glen Haven, Bowen Mountain, Grand Lake, McHenrys Peak, Longs Peak, Panorama Peak, Trail Mountain, Shadow Mountain, Isolation Peak, Allens Park, Raymond, Granby, Strawberry Lake, Monarch Lake, Ward, and Gold Hill. For more information refer to the USGS_DEM User's Guide available on-line at: &lt;URL:http://edcwww.cr.usgs.gov/glis/hyper/guide/usgs_dem&gt;.</abstract><purpose>Data used and/or developed by the Rocky Mountain National Park GIS Program is used in the protection and Management of Rocky Mountain National Park.</purpose><langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>19900101</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>publication date</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>None planned</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc Sync="TRUE">-106.136959</westbc><eastbc Sync="TRUE">-105.123169</eastbc><northbc Sync="TRUE">40.755450</northbc><southbc Sync="TRUE">39.994628</southbc></bounding><lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">404016.030123</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">489486.030123</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4427556.268909</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">4511406.268909</topbc></lboundng></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>none</themekt><themekey>Rocky Mountain National Park</themekey><themekey>Digital Elevation Model (DEM)</themekey><themekey>United States Geological Survey (USGS)</themekey><themekey>elevation</themekey><themekey>topography</themekey></theme><place><placekt>none</placekt><placekey>Rocky Mountain National Park</placekey><placekey>Colorado</placekey><placekey>Larimer County</placekey><placekey>Boulder County</placekey><placekey>Grand County</placekey><placekey>Estes Park</placekey><placekey>Grand Lake</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>Not for use at scales greater than 1:24000</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>GIS Coordinator</cntper><cntorg>Rocky Mountain National Park GIS Program</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>US Hwy 36</address><city>Estes Park</city><state>Colorado</state><postal>80517</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>N/A</cntvoice><cntemail>romo_gis_coordinator@nps.gov</cntemail><cntfax>(970) 586-1392</cntfax></cntinfo></ptcontac><native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</native><natvform Sync="TRUE">Raster Dataset</natvform></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>The attribute accuracy is deductively estimated to be "good". If a higher proof of data accuracy is required, do not use this data. User is advised to FULLY and CAREFULLY READ the "DISTRIBUTION LIABILITY" section of this metadata before using this data.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Not applicable for raster data.</logic><complete>Data is considered complete. Some datasets are parkwide in scope, while others were developed and/or updated to address specific management concerns within particular spatial coordinates. Users of this data are advised to FULLY and CAREFULLY READ the "DISTRIBUTION LIABILITY" section of this</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Horizontal accuracy varies depending on the source of individual components within the data. Data derived from USGS data (DLGs, DEMs, DOQQs) are assumed to meet National Map Accuracy standards, though extensive experience in using USGS data for the Rocky Mountain National Park area has shown that many data coponents have spatial errors exceeding the National Map Accuracy standards. Data produced from GPS (Global Positioning System) field data is assumed to be spatially accurate to within 2-5 meters.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc>Rocky Mountain National Park (ROMO) acquired 25 Level 1 Digital Elevation Model (DEM) data files in 1990. The USGS DEM data files were imported into Geographic Resource Analysis Support System (GRASS) software using the "m.dem.extract" command. Areas of "no-data" gaps were identified, and these gaps were filled using a 3x3 matrix filter (for gaps 1 cell wide) or a 5x5 matrix filter (for gaps 2 or 3 cells wide). 

The process of filtering the gaps involved creating a region (mapextent) 1 cell wider than the gap on both sides of the gap and running the matrix filter on that small amount of data using the GRASS command "r.mfilter". The cell file containing the results of the filtering was then patched back into the DEM coverage using the GRASS command "r.patch". 

No smoothing was performed to reduce the horizontal striping which is characteristic in Level 1 DEM data and which is evident in this data. 

The GRASS raster data was converted to an ARC/INFO lattice coverage using the ARC/INFO command IMAGEGRID. The ARC/INFO TABLES module was used to add a FEET item and to populate that item. This was accomplished by multipying the VALUE item by 3.280839895. 

For detailed information about how the individual DEM data files were created see the USGS_DEM User's Guide available on-line at: &lt;URL:http://edcwww.cr.usgs.gov/glis/hyper/guide/usgs_dem&gt;. 


</procdesc><procdate>19900101</procdate>
Rocky Mountain National Park (ROMO) acquired 25 Level 1 Digital Elevation Model (DEM) data files in 1990. The USGS DEM data files were imported into Geographic Resource Analysis Support System (GRASS) software using the "m.dem.extract" command. Areas of "no-data" gaps were identified, and these gaps were filled using a 3x3 matrix filter (for gaps 1 cell wide) or a 5x5 matrix filter (for gaps 2 or 3 cells wide). The process of filtering the gaps involved creating a region (mapextent) 1 cell wider than the gap on both sides of the gap and running the matrix filter on that small amount of data using the GRASS command "r.mfilter". The cell file containing the results of the filtering was then patched back into the DEM coverage using the GRASS command "r.patch". No smoothing was performed to reduce the horizontal striping which is characteristic in Level 1 DEM data and which is evident in this data. The GRASS raster data was converted to an ARC/INFO lattice coverage using the ARC/INFO command IMAGEGRID. The ARC/INFO TABLES module was used to add a FEET item and to populate that item. This was accomplished by multipying the VALUE item by 3.280839895. For detailed information about how the individual DEM data files were created see the USGS_DEM User's Guide available on-line at:         &lt;URL:http://edcwww.cr.usgs.gov/glis/hyper/guide/usgs_dem&gt;.
</procstep><procstep><procdesc>The base template for this metadata created using ROMOMETA.AML, a locally modified version (modified June 1998) of FGDCMETA.AML ver. 1.2 05/14/98 on ARC/INFO data set /db/topo/elev_dem</procdesc><procdate>19980803</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Metadata converted from html to xml</procdesc><date Sync="TRUE">20050901</date><time Sync="TRUE">16023300</time><proccont><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Data Manager - Brent Frakes</cntper><cntorg>ROMN</cntorg></cntperp></cntinfo></proccont><procdate>20050901</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">Z:\GEODATA\ROMO\DEM\romo_dem30\metadata.xml</srcused><date Sync="TRUE">20060217</date><time Sync="TRUE">15243400</time></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">Z:\GEODATA\ROMO\DEM\romo_dem30.img</srcused><date Sync="TRUE">20060628</date><time Sync="TRUE">09235200</time></procstep></lineage><metadata><NPS_Info><MetaPurp>NPS</MetaPurp><NPS_Unit><UnitCode>MANDATORY: NPS Alpha Unit Code (ACAD)</UnitCode><UnitType>MANDATORY: NPS Unit Type (National Park, National Monument, etc)</UnitType></NPS_Unit><Std_Info><SObjName>MANDATORY: Name of NRDT or GIS Layer Standard</SObjName><SType>MANDATORY: Standard Type (GIS or NRDT)</SType><StatInfo><SStatus>MANDATORY: Standard Status</SStatus></StatInfo></Std_Info></NPS_Info><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>MANDATORY: The originator of the data</origin><title>MANDATORY: The title of the data being documented</title></citeinfo></citation><keywords><theme><themekt>National Park Service Theme Category Thesaurus</themekt></theme><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt></theme><theme><themekt>None</themekt></theme><place><placekt>National Park System Unit Name Thesaurus</placekt></place><place><placekt>National Park System Unit Code Thesaurus</placekt></place><place><placekt>None</placekt></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>None</useconst></idinfo><distinfo><distliab>The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on computer systems at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</distliab><stdorder><fees>None</fees></stdorder></distinfo><metainfo><metd>MANDATORY: Use YYYYMMDD format</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://nrdata.nps.gov/profiles/NPS_Profile.xml</onlink><metprof>NPS NR and GIS Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>


before using this data.</metadata></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct Sync="TRUE">Raster</direct><rastinfo><rasttype Sync="TRUE">Pixel</rasttype><rowcount Sync="TRUE">2795</rowcount><colcount Sync="TRUE">2849</colcount><rastxsz Sync="TRUE">30.000000</rastxsz><rastysz Sync="TRUE">30.000000</rastysz><rastbpp Sync="TRUE">16</rastbpp><vrtcount Sync="TRUE">1</vrtcount><rastorig Sync="TRUE">Upper Left</rastorig><rastcmap Sync="TRUE">FALSE</rastcmap><rastcomp Sync="TRUE">Run-Length Encoding (ESRI)</rastcomp><rastband Sync="TRUE">1</rastband><rastdtyp Sync="TRUE">pixel codes</rastdtyp><rastplyr Sync="TRUE">TRUE</rastplyr><rastifor Sync="TRUE">ERDAS IMAGINE</rastifor></rastinfo></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><planci><plance Sync="TRUE">row and column</plance><coordrep><absres Sync="TRUE">30.000000</absres><ordres Sync="TRUE">30.000000</ordres></coordrep><plandu Sync="TRUE">meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1927</horizdn><ellips Sync="TRUE">Clarke 1866</ellips><semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378206.400000</semiaxis><denflat Sync="TRUE">294.978698</denflat></geodetic><cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1927</geogcsn><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1927_UTM_Zone_13N</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys></spref><eainfo><overview><eaover>The first two items in the value attribute table (VAT) are automatically generated by ARC/INFO software. Contact ESRI or read their literature for detailed descriptions of their internal file structure. ESRI (Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc.) can be reached at: &lt;URL:http://www.esri.com&gt;. (Link valid July 1998). The VALUE item is a numeric field that is populated by a value that represents the elevation in meters. The COUNT item is a numeric field that is populated by a value that represents the number of cells that have a given VALUE. The FEET item is a numeric field that is populated by a value that represents the elevation in feet and was created by multiplying the VALUE item by 3.280839895.</eaover><eadetcit>none</eadetcit></overview><detailed Name="romo_dem.vat"><enttyp><enttypl Sync="TRUE">romo_dem.vat</enttypl><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Table</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">65</enttypc></enttyp><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Rowid</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Rowid</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Value</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">VALUE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Count</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">COUNT</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Rocky Mountain National Park GIS Program</cntorg></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>US Hwy 36</address><city>Estes Park</city><state>Colorado</state><postal>80517</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>N/A</cntvoice><cntemail>romo_gis_coordinator@nps.gov</cntemail><cntinst>Contact via email</cntinst></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (if available) are not legal documents and are not iintended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistant within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. Any related graphics (if available) are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on another system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data. All World Wide Web addresses were valid when this metadata was created.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><transize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transize><dssize Sync="TRUE">0.000</dssize></digtinfo></digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder><resdesc Sync="TRUE">Downloadable Data</resdesc></distinfo><metainfo><metd Sync="TRUE">20060217</metd><metrd>20000406</metrd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Rocky Mountain National Park GIS Program</cntorg><cntper>GIS Coordinator</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>US Hwy 36</address><city>Estes Park</city><state>Colorado</state><postal>80517</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>N/A</cntvoice><cntemail>romo_gis_coordinator@nps.gov</cntemail><cntfax>(970) 586-1392</cntfax></cntinfo></metc><metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><metadata><NPS_Info><MetaPurp>NPS</MetaPurp><NPS_Unit><UnitCode>MANDATORY: NPS Alpha Unit Code (ACAD)</UnitCode><UnitType>MANDATORY: NPS Unit Type (National Park, National Monument, etc)</UnitType></NPS_Unit><Std_Info><SObjName>MANDATORY: Name of NRDT or GIS Layer Standard</SObjName><SType>MANDATORY: Standard Type (GIS or NRDT)</SType><StatInfo><SStatus>MANDATORY: Standard Status</SStatus></StatInfo></Std_Info></NPS_Info><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>MANDATORY: The originator of the data</origin><title>MANDATORY: The title of the data being documented</title></citeinfo></citation><keywords><theme><themekt>National Park Service Theme Category Thesaurus</themekt></theme><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt></theme><theme><themekt>None</themekt></theme><place><placekt>National Park System Unit Name Thesaurus</placekt></place><place><placekt>National Park System Unit Code Thesaurus</placekt></place><place><placekt>None</placekt></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>None</useconst></idinfo><distinfo><distliab>The National Park Service shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. The National Park Service gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from an NPS server and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on computer systems at the National Park Service, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</distliab><stdorder><fees>None</fees></stdorder></distinfo><metainfo><metd>MANDATORY: Use YYYYMMDD format</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://nrdata.nps.gov/profiles/NPS_Profile.xml</onlink><metprof>NPS NR and GIS Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo></metadata><langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc></metainfo><Esri><CreaDate>20060628</CreaDate><CreaTime>09235100</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20140611</SyncDate><SyncTime>15593100</SyncTime><ModDate>20140611</ModDate><ModTime>15593100</ModTime><MetaID>{66B1FD2D-F5B7-47F3-94B0-08750BE85C96}</MetaID><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">ROMO_DEM</itemName><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://D:\RouteTestingWorkspace\ROMO_data\ROMO_TestShapes\ROMO_DEM</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">448326.030123</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">449076.030123</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4468716.268909</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">4469406.268909</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1927</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Meter (1.000000)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1927_UTM_Zone_13N</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.1'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;NAD_1927_UTM_Zone_13N&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1927&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1927&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;Clarke_1866&amp;quot;,6378206.4,294.9786982]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Transverse_Mercator&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,500000.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-105.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Scale_Factor&amp;quot;,0.9996],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;,26713]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-5121000&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-9998000&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;450450052.74759901&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;26713&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;26713&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><RasterProperties><General><PixelDepth Sync="TRUE">16</PixelDepth><HasColormap Sync="TRUE">FALSE</HasColormap><CompressionType Sync="TRUE">RLE</CompressionType><NumBands Sync="TRUE">1</NumBands><Format Sync="TRUE">GRID</Format><HasPyramids Sync="TRUE">TRUE</HasPyramids><SourceType Sync="TRUE">continuous</SourceType><PixelType Sync="TRUE">signed integer</PixelType><NoDataValue Sync="TRUE">0</NoDataValue></General></RasterProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="d:\arcgis\desktop10.2\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Clip" Date="20140611" Time="155931">Clip romo_dem30.img "448337.884948298 4468739.08356027 449049.258472404 4469402.23733232" D:\RouteTestingWorkspace\ROMO_data\ROMO_TestShapes\ROMO_DEM cutter2 0 NONE NO_MAINTAIN_EXTENT</Process></lineage></DataProperties></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.2.2.3552</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="eng"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">ROMO_DEM</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="002"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">404016.030123</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">489486.030123</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">4511406.268909</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4427556.268909</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-106.136959</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-105.123169</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">40.75545</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">39.994628</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode><westBL Sync="TRUE">-105.608697</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-105.599808</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">40.375581</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">40.369318</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="eng"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\10.147.158.195\ROMN\PROJECTS\ROMN\158_ROMN_CostSurfaceModelDevelopment\Data\original_data\romo_dem30.img</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Raster Dataset</formatName></distorFormat></distributor><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Raster Dataset</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE" code="26713">NAD_1927_UTM_Zone_13N</identCode><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">8.2.6</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><GridSpatRep><numDims Sync="TRUE">2</numDims><cellGeo><CellGeoCd Sync="TRUE" value="002"></CellGeoCd></cellGeo><tranParaAv Sync="TRUE">1</tranParaAv><axDimProps><Dimen><dimName><DimNameTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="002"></DimNameTypCd></dimName><dimSize Sync="TRUE">2849</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE">30</value><uom><UomLength><uomName Sync="TRUE">Meter</uomName><conversionToISOstandardUnit Sync="TRUE">1 Meter = 1 Meter(s)</conversionToISOstandardUnit></UomLength></uom></dimResol></Dimen><Dimen><dimName><DimNameTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></DimNameTypCd></dimName><dimSize Sync="TRUE">2795</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE">30</value><uom><UomLength><uomName Sync="TRUE">Meter</uomName><conversionToISOstandardUnit Sync="TRUE">1 Meter = 1 Meter(s)</conversionToISOstandardUnit></UomLength></uom></dimResol></Dimen></axDimProps></GridSpatRep><Georect><cellGeo><CellGeoCd Sync="TRUE" value="002"></CellGeoCd></cellGeo><numDims Sync="TRUE">2</numDims><tranParaAv Sync="TRUE">1</tranParaAv><chkPtAv Sync="TRUE">0</chkPtAv><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">448326.030123 4468716.268909</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">448326.030123 4469406.268909</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">449076.030123 4469406.268909</pos></cornerPts><cornerPts><pos Sync="TRUE">449076.030123 4468716.268909</pos></cornerPts><centerPt><pos Sync="TRUE">448701.030123 4469061.268909</pos></centerPt><axisDimension type="002"><dimSize Sync="TRUE">25</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE" uom="Meter">30.000000</value></dimResol></axisDimension><axisDimension type="001"><dimSize Sync="TRUE">23</dimSize><dimResol><value Sync="TRUE" uom="Meter">30.000000</value></dimResol></axisDimension><ptInPixel><PixOrientCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></PixOrientCd></ptInPixel></Georect></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20140611</mdDateSt><contInfo><ImgDesc><contentTyp><ContentTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="003"></ContentTypCd></contentTyp><covDim><Band><dimDescrp Sync="TRUE">Band_1</dimDescrp><maxVal Sync="TRUE">2602.000000</maxVal><minVal Sync="TRUE">2536.000000</minVal><bitsPerVal Sync="TRUE">16</bitsPerVal><valUnit><UOM type="length"></UOM></valUnit></Band></covDim></ImgDesc></contInfo></metadata>
